[part2有个主持人] First of all, let me thank you all for coming to this public meeting, to discuss the future of our town.
Our first speaker is Shona Ferguson, from Barford town council. Shona.
(Q11（单选）) [🟢◾️题干定位词 buses出现，] Thank you. First I'll briefly give you some background information, then I'll be asking you for your comments on developments in the town.
[Q11答案句 ✅C 只在乘客多的线路安排bus= 没有那么多线路了 ， 以及， 判断出题目有fewer，【程度】考点，又听到程度词most 就必须关注] Well, as you don't need me to tell you, Barford has changed a great deal in the last 50 years. These are some of the main changes.
[Q11答案句 ✅C 只在乘客多的线路安排bus= 没有那么多线路了 ， 以及， 判断出题目有fewer，【程度】考点，又听到程度词most 就必须关注] Fifty years ago, buses linked virtually every part of the town and the neighbouring towns and villages.
[Q11答案句 ✅C 只在乘客多的线路安排bus= 没有那么多线路了 ， 以及， 判断出题目有fewer，【程度】考点，又听到程度词most 就必须关注] Most people used them frequently, but not now, because the bus companies concentrate on just the routes that attract most passengers.
So parts of the town are no longer served by buses.
[❌A 断章取义： 原文说 就算把old&uncomfortable换了， 也没用（have little impact）] Even replacing old uncomfortable buses with smart new ones has had little impact on passenger numbers.
[❌B 否定原文： 明确否定票价涨幅过大] It's sometimes said that bus fares are too high, but in relation to average incomes, fares are not much higher than they were 50 years ago.
(Q12) [🟢◾️Q12 定位词 road network出现 （名词），🟠考点词： benefit+ most 程度+态度] Changes in the road network are affecting the town.
[❌C：偷换概念 且程度不一，center was closed to traffic 虽然是banning of cars， 但效果还在评估， 断章取义] The centre was recently closed to traffic on a trial basis, making it much safer for pedestrians.
[但效果还在评估 —— 断章取义 ❌C] The impact of this is being measured.
[Q12答案句 ✅选项B cycle path原词， be used far more than = 在选项发展； reducing+improving 都表示题干的benefit] The new cycle paths, separating bikes from cars in most main roads, are being used far more than was expected, reducing traffic and improving air quality.
[❌A否定原文， bypass这个想法 have failed] And although the council's attempts to have a bypass constructed have failed, we haven't given up hope of persuading the government to change its mind.
(Q13) [🟢◾️定位词shopping （名词），🟠考点词 判断为 problem（态度）] Shopping in the town centre has changed over the years.
[无考点词，有🟢◾️定位词medical facilities ❌B 虽然提到了medical practices， 但 plan相关的事未提及，无中生有。] Many of us can remember when the town was crowded with people going shopping.
[❌A 否定原文， despite提供停车场，数字还是falling] Numbers have been falling for several years, despite efforts to attract shoppers, for instance by opening new car parks.
[❌C 断章取义， 说的只是有些人会把两件事（restaurant&cafe）合在一起干。] Some people combine shopping with visits to the town's restaurants and cafes.
[Q13答案句 ✅B， 说大家更愿意去的是 📚well known chain store = major retailer 【同义替换】] Most shops are small independent stores, which is good, but many people prefer to use supermarkets and department stores in nearby large towns, as there are so few well-known chain stores here.
(Q14) [无考点词，有🟢◾️定位词medical facilities ❌B 虽然提到了medical practices， 但 plan相关的事未提及，无中生有。] Turning now to medical facilities, the town is served by family doctors in several medical practices - fewer than 50 years ago, but each catering for far more patients.
[Q14答案句 ✅A， 15年前close了，那就是现在no hospital] Our hospital closed 15 years ago, which means journeys to other towns are unavoidable.
[❌C 否定原文，  选项too low，原文more detists than used to be，] On the other hand, there are more dentists than there used to be.
(Q15) [🟢◾️定位词顺延寻找：已画出employ——题干be  employed in📚同义替换定位（换词性）。 🟠考点词：程度 largest] Employment patterns have changed, along with almost everything else.
[Q15答案句 ✅C， main sector = 题干largest number of people， 📚 schools and colleges 🟰 education] The number of schools and colleges has increased, making that the main employment sector.
[❌A，变得重要 也不等于 最多人从事， 偷换概念] Services, such as website design and accountancy, have grown in importance,
(Q16（配对）) [❌B 未见衰退 不等于largest number of people， 偷换概念/断章取义] and surprisingly, perhaps, manufacturing hasn't seen the decline that has affected it in other parts of the country.
Now I'll very quickly outline current plans for some of the town's facilities, before asking for your comments.
As you'll know if you regularly use the car park at the railway station, it's usually full.
The railway company applied for permission to replace it with a multi-storey car park, but that was refused.
Instead, the company has bought some adjoining land, and this will be used to increase the number of parking spaces.
The Grand, the old cinema in the high street, will close at the end of the year, and reopen on a different site.
You've probably seen the building under construction.
The plan is to have three screens with fewer seats, rather than just the one large auditorium in the old cinema.
I expect many of you shop in the indoor market.
It's become more and more shabby-looking, and because of fears about safety, it was threatened with demolition.
The good news is that it will close for six weeks to be made safe and redecorated, and the improved building will open in July.
Lots of people use the library, including school and college students who go there to study.
The council has managed to secure funding to keep the library open later into the evening, twice a week.
We would like to enlarge the building in the not-too-distant future, but this is by no means definite.
There's no limit on access to the nature reserve on the edge of town, and this will continue to be the case.
What will change, though, is that the council will no longer be in charge of the area.
Instead it will become the responsibility of a national body that administers most nature reserves in the country.
OK, now let me ask you…